Damien Hervieux

Address: 162-0061, Tokyo-to, Shinjuku-ku, Ichigaya-yanagicho, 26, Roje, KR 302

Tel: 080 2982 1443 Nationality: France

Birth: 11/26/85

Visa: Spouse Visa

Webpage: https://www.dherv.com

Email: damien.herv@gmail.com

FullStack Developer

I started my career in June 2018 and worked on various projects since then. I'am currently living in Tokyo with my family with whom I usually spend my free time. I also enjoy studying programming, watching movies and practicing jiujitsu.

Experience

FullStack Developer - Rooking, Tokyo

2018 - present

The company is developing full stack applications using mainly Laravel or Django on the backend and Vue or React on the frontend. It recently started moving towards Django and React as a main stack. Some projects I worked on also required me to use different technologies like ElasticSearch or Lambda.

We usually develop our applications using Docker and deploy them on AWS, using EC2, S3, RDS or ElasticBeanStalk.

Barista - Tokyo and Melbourne

2013 to 2017

I used to be a barista in different coffee shops in Australia and Japan.

Project Manager - Publicis, Paris

2010 to 2012

The project manager role was to coordinate the projects for Renault-Nissan's communication (automobile) for a car launch or a new version, to manage the budget, the schedule and the communication between designers, production and client.

Each project involved a movie production, a photo shoot and papers production (ex: product book, magazine, etc.) or updating existing content for a new version.

Project Manager - Internships in Grenoble (France)

2009 - 2010

I used to organize amateur and professional events related to the surf, snow, skate area.

Skills

Front-End - Typescript, Javascript with ES6, React, Vue, Angular, HTML, CSS, GatsbyJS, NextJS

Back-End - Laravel, Django, NodeJS, Python, MySQL, NestJS, Fastify, ElasticSearch, Redis

Testing - Jest, Enzyme

Tools - Webpack, Visual Studio Code, JetBrains (PyCharm, ...), EsLint/TSLint, Prettier, Figma, Trello/Jira, Github/GitLab, SourceTree, Postman, Slack

DevOps - AWS S3, AWS Lambda, AWS EC2, AWS ElasticBeanStalk, AWS RDS, CircleCl

Wanted - Rust, Machine Learning, Kotlin, Swift, React Native, GraphQL, PWA

Languages

English - Fluent

French - Native

Japanese - Basic to Conversational

Education

Master of Economics and Business - Grenoble (France) - 2009

Bachelor Degree of Economics - Le Mans (France) - 2006

High school degree, major in Science - Le Mans (France) - 2002